Finding Aid of the Midwest Archives Conference Records, 1972-2014
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
- Records, 1972-2014, UWM Manuscript Collection 194; 42.1 cubic ft. (112 boxes) 1,083 digital files (171 MB)
  - 6. Meetings, 1972-2014
    - Spring 2005
      - Electronic Records, 2005 Spring, Chicago
      - Local Arrangements Committee, 2004-2005 (Box 111, Folder 4)
      - Program, 2005 (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - Fall 2005
      - Electronic Records, 2005 Fall, Bloomington
      - Local Arrangements Committee, 2003-2006 (Box 111, Folder 6-8)
      - Program, 2005 (Box 111, Folder 9)
    - Spring 2006
      - Electronic Records, 2006 Spring, Bloomington
      - Program, 2006 (Box 111, Folder 10)
    - Fall 2006
      - Electronic Records, 2006 Fall, Omaha
      - Program, 2006 (Box 115, Folder 10)
    - Spring 2007
      - Electronic Records, 2007 Spring, Columbus
      - Program, 2007 (Box 111, Folder 11)
    - Fall 2007
      - Electronic Records, 2007 Fall, Cranbrook
    - Spring 2008
      - Electronic Records, 2008 Spring, Louisville
      - Local Arrangements Committee, 2007-2008 (Box 111, Folder 12)
      - Program, 2008 (Box 111, Folder 13)
    - Fall 2008
      - Electronic Records, 2008 Fall, Lawrence
      - Symposium Packet, 2008 (Box 111, Folder 14)
    - Spring 2009
      - Electronic Records, 2009 Spring, St. Louis
      - Local Arrangements Committee, 2009 (Box 118, Folder 7)
      - Meeting Packet, 2009 (Box 118, Folder 8)
      - Program, 2009 (Box 111, Folder 15)
    - Fall 2009
      - Electronic Records, 2009 Fall, Madison
    - Spring 2010
      - Electronic Records, 2010 Spring, Chicago
      - Meeting Packet, 2010 (Box 118, Folder 9)
      - Program, 2010 (Box 111, Folder 16)
    - Fall 2010
      - Electronic Records, 2010 Fall, Dayton
    - Spring 2011
      - Electronic Records, 2011 Spring, St. Paul
    - Fall 2011
      - Brochure, 2011 (Box 118, Folder 10)
      - Electronic Records, 2011 Fall, Sioux City
      - Organizing Committee, 2010 (Box 118, Folder 11)
    - Spring 2012
      - Electronic Records, 2012 Spring, Grand Rapids
    - Fall 2012
      - Electronic Records, 2012 Fall, Cincinnati
    - Spring 2013
      - Electronic Records, 2013 Spring, Indianapolis
    - Fall 2013
      - Electronic Records, 2013 Fall, Green Bay
      - Flyer, 2013 (Box 115, Folder 17)
    - Spring 2014
      - Electronic Records, 2014 Spring, Kansas City
    - Spring 2015
      - Electronic Records, 2015 Spring, Lexington
  - 7. Publications, 1972-2010
    - A. Calendar, 1992-2001
      The MAC Calendars note dates of importance to archivists. Each month features a photograph from an archives in the MAC region.
      - 1992-1995 (Box 80, Folder 1)
      - 1996-2001 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - B. Journal, 1976-2014
      Collection includes a complete set of MAC's semi-annual journal, The Midwestern Archivist (1976-1991) and Archival Issues (1992-present). Articles relate to archival theory and current practice, archival history, and aspects of related professions of interest to archivists, such as records management and conservation management. The journal also contains seminar proceedings, case studies, and book reviews.
      Back issues of Archival Issues are available in MINDS@UW, the institutional repository of the University of Wisconsin System. The most recent full volume is embargoed for one year.
      - The Midwestern Archivist
        - Vols. 1-8, 1976-1983 (Box 81, Folder 1-8)
        - Index, Vol. 1-8, 1987-1983 (Box 81, Folder 9)
        - Vols. 9-13, 1984-1988 (Box 81, Folder 10-14)
        - Vols. 14-16, 1989-1991 (Box 82, Folder 1-3)
      - Archival Issues
        - Vols. 17-20, 1992-1995 (Box 82, Folder 4-7)
        - Index, Vols. 9-21, 1984-1996 (Box 82, Folder 8)
        - Vols. 21-27, 1996-2002 (Box 82, Folder 9-15)
        - Vols. 28-35, 2003-2013/2014 (Box 109, Folder 1-7)
    - C. Newsletter, 1973-2010
      Collection includes a complete set of MAC newsletters. (N.B. Vol. 5, no. 4 was not published.) The newsletter provides information about meetings, committees, Council, repositories, publications, Web sites, members, awards, jobs, current issues, as well as other news related to the archives profession.
      - Vols. 1-17, 1973-1990 (Box 98, Folder 1-8)
      - Vols. 18-30, 1990-2003 (Box 99, Folder 1-8)
      - Vols. 31-37, 2003-2010 (Box 100, Folder 1-7)
  - 8. Journal Editorial Board, 1974-1999
    - A. Administrative Files, 1974-1999
      These records largely include correspondence with other board members and individuals who submitted articles for publication; and minutes and reports pertaining to the status of articles, book reviews, and the journal's production. Also included are files on advertising and production costs, review guidelines, and the journal's name change.
      Files pertaining to manuscript reviews are restricted for 15 years.
      - Advertising, 1978-1986 (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - Analysis of Midwestern Archivist, 1986 (Box 83, Folder 2)
      - Assignment of Copyright, 1978-1980, undated (Box 83, Folder 3)
      - Book Reviews, 1980 (Box 83, Folder 4)
      - Budget, 1981-1985 (Box 83, Folder 5)
      - Case Study Guidelines, 1983-1985 (Box 83, Folder 6)
      - Copyright Registration, 1976-1989 (Box 83, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence, 1974-1983 (Box 83, Folder 8-12)
      - Correspondence, 1984-1989 (Box 84, Folder 1-4)
      - Correspondence, 1990-1994 (Box 84, Folder 5-8)
        Restricted
      - Correspondence, 1995-1999 (Box 85, Folder 1-2)
      - Correspondence, Samples, 1979-1984 (Box 85, Folder 3)
      - Costs, 1986-1987 (Box 85, Folder 4)
      - Editorial Board, 1976-1988 (Box 85, Folder 5)
      - Guidelines, 1976-1991 (Box 85, Folder 6)
      - Index, Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 85, Folder 7)
      - Index, Proposal, 1995-1997 (Box 85, Folder 8)
      - Indexing and Abstracting Services, 1976-1985 (Box 85, Folder 9)
      - ISSN Number, 1983-1986 (Box 85, Folder 10)
      - Memos to Board, 1990-1991 (Box 85, Folder 11)
      - Minutes, 1975-1993 (Box 85, Folder 12)
      - Name Change, 1990-1992 (Box 85, Folder 13)
      - NHPRC Consultants' Reports, 1983 (Box 85, Folder 14)
      - Norton Award, 1984-1985 (Box 85, Folder 15)
      - Production, 1978-1985 (Box 85, Folder 16)
      - Questionnaire, 1977 (Box 85, Folder 17)
      - Regional Archival Networks Conference, 1981 (Box 85, Folder 18)
      - Reports, 1975-1987 (Box 86, Folder 1-5)
      - Reports, 1990-1996 (Box 86, Folder 6)
      - Reprints, 1986-1987 (Box 86, Folder 7)
      - Volunteers, 1981 (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - B. Accepted Journal Article Files, 1974-1998
      Files contain review forms, correspondence, and drafts of articles submitted for publication. Arranged by journal volume, these files also contain "Assignment of Rights" forms.
      These records are restricted for 15 years from the date of the review.
      - Vol. 1 (1), Burckel, 1974 (Box 87, Folder 1)
      - Vol. 1 (1), Fogerty, 1976 (Box 87, Folder 2)
      - Vol. 1 (1), Walch, 1976 (Box 87, Folder 3)
      - Vol. 1 (2), Hackman, 1976 (Box 87, Folder 4)
      - Vol. 2 (1), Quinn, 1976-1977 (Box 87, Folder 5)
      - Vol. 2 (1), von Kohl, 1977 (Box 87, Folder 6)
      - Vol. 2 (2), Noble, 1977 (Box 87, Folder 7)
      - Vol. 3 (1), 1978 (Box 87, Folder 8)
      - Vol. 3 (2), 1978 (Box 87, Folder 9)
      - Vol. 3 (2), Fleckner, 1978 (Box 87, Folder 10)
      - Vol. 4 (1), 1979 (Box 87, Folder 11)
      - Vol. 4 (2), 1979 (Box 87, Folder 12)
      - Vol. 5 (1), 1980 (Box 87, Folder 13)
      - Vol. 5 (2), 1981 (Box 87, Folder 14)
      - Vol. 5 (2), Theoharis, 1981 (Box 87, Folder 15)
      - Vol. 6 (1), 1981 (Box 87, Folder 16)
      - Vol. 7 (1), 1980-1981 (Box 87, Folder 17)
      - Vol. 7 (2), 1980-1982 (Box 87, Folder 18)
      - Vol. 8 (1), 1980-1982 (Box 87, Folder 19)
      - Vol. 8 (1), Lankford, 1983 (Box 87, Folder 20)
      - Vol. 8 (1), Sturzenberger, 1983 (Box 87, Folder 21)
      - Vol. 8 (2), 1983 (Box 87, Folder 22)
      - Vol. 9 (1), 1984 (Box 87, Folder 23)
      - Vol. 9 (2), Forston-Jones, 1983-1984 (Box 87, Folder 24)
      - Vol. 9 (2), Motley, 1984 (Box 87, Folder 25)
      - Vol. 9 (2), O'Toole, 1984 (Box 87, Folder 26)
      - Vol. 9 (2), Spear, 1984 (Box 87, Folder 27)
      - Vol. 10 (1), Cox, 1985 (Box 87, Folder 28)
      - Vol. 10 (1), Engst, 1985 (Box 87, Folder 29)
      - Vol. 10 (1), Gracy II, 1985 (Box 87, Folder 30)
      - Vol. 10 (1), Hage, 1985 (Box 87, Folder 31)
      - Vol. 10 (1), Stewart, 1985 (Box 87, Folder 32)
      - Vol. 10 (1), Warner, 1985 (Box 87, Folder 33)
      - Vol. 10 (2), 1985 (Box 88, Folder 1)
      - Vol. 10 (2), Freeman, 1985 (Box 88, Folder 2)
      - Vol. 10 (2), Stewart, 1985 (Box 88, Folder 3)
      - Vol. 10 (2), Walle, 1985 (Box 88, Folder 4)
      - Vol. 11 (1), Conway, 1986 (Box 88, Folder 5)
      - Vol. 11 (1), Evans, 1986 (Box 88, Folder 6)
      - Vol. 11(1), Goggin, 1986 (Box 88, Folder 7)
      - Vol. 11 (1), Maher, 1986 (Box 88, Folder 8)
      - Vol. 11 (1), Turnbough, 1986 (Box 88, Folder 9)
      - Vol. 11 (2), 1986 (Box 88, Folder 10)
      - Vol. 11 (2), Bradsher, 1986 (Box 88, Folder 11)
      - Vol. 11 (2), Cloud, 1986 (Box 88, Folder 12)
      - Vol. 12 (1), 1987 (Box 88, Folder 13)
      - Vol. 12 (1), Adams, 1987 (Box 88, Folder 14)
      - Vol. 12 (1), Carleton, 1987 (Box 88, Folder 15)
      - Vol. 12 (2), 1987 (Box 88, Folder 16)
      - Vol. 12 (2), Ericksen, 1986-1987 (Box 88, Folder 17)
      - Vol. 13 (1), 1988 (Box 88, Folder 18)
      - Vol. 13 (1), Burton, 1987-1988 (Box 88, Folder 19)
      - Vol. 13 (2), 1988 (Box 88, Folder 20)
      - Vol. 14 (1), Barritt, 1989 (Box 88, Folder 21)
      - Vol. 14 (1), Davis, 1989 (Box 88, Folder 22)
      - Vol. 14 (1), Garrison, 1989 (Box 88, Folder 23)
      - Vol. 14 (1), Greene, 1989 (Box 88, Folder 24)
      - Vol. 14 (1), Tatem, 1989 (Box 88, Folder 25)
      - Vol. 14 (2), Burkel, 1989 (Box 89, Folder 1)
      - Vol. 14 (2), Ham, 1989 (Box 89, Folder 2)
      - Vol. 14 (2), Newborg, 1989 (Box 89, Folder 3)
      - Vol. 15 (1), Cox, 1990 (Box 89, Folder 4)
      - Vol. 15 (1), Floyd, 1990 (Box 89, Folder 5)
      - Vol. 15 (1), Klaassen, 1990 (Box 89, Folder 6)
      - Vol. 15 (1), Meissner, 1990 (Box 89, Folder 7)
      - Vol. 16 (1), Gallagher, 1990-1991 (Box 89, Folder 8)
      - Vol. 16 (2), DeWitt, 1990-1991 (Box 89, Folder 9)
      - Vol. 16 (2), Freeman, 1991 (Box 89, Folder 10)
      - Vol. 16 (2), Greene, 1990-1991 (Box 89, Folder 11)
      - Vol. 16 (2), Maher, 1990-1991 (Box 89, Folder 12)
      - Vol. 17 (1), Hite/Linke, 1992 (Box 89, Folder 13)
      - Vol. 17 (1), Morrissey, 1992 (Box 89, Folder 14)
      - Vol. 18 (2), Ambacher, 1993 (Box 89, Folder 15)
      - Vol. 19 (1), 1996 (Box 89, Folder 16)
      - Vol. 19 (2), 1996 (Box 89, Folder 17)
      - Vol. 20 (1), 1996 (Box 89, Folder 18)
      - Vol. 20 (2), Cox, 1995 (Box 89, Folder 19)
      - Vol. 20 (2), Finch, 1995 (Box 89, Folder 20)
      - Vol. 20 (2), Lamoree, 1995 (Box 89, Folder 21)
      - Vol. 20 (2), Su, 1995 (Box 89, Folder 22)
      - Vol. 21 (1), Bain, 1996 (Box 90, Folder 1)
      - Vol. 21 (1), Boles, 1996 (Box 90, Folder 2)
      - Vol. 21 (1), Garrison, 1996 (Box 90, Folder 3)
      - Vol. 21 (1), Sturgeon, 1996 (Box 90, Folder 4)
      - Vol. 21 (2), Barata, 1996 (Box 90, Folder 5)
      - Vol. 21 (2), Kayplan/Mifflin, 1996 (Box 90, Folder 6)
      - Vol. 21 (2), Menninger, 1996 (Box 90, Folder 7)
      - Vol. 21 (2), Neal, 1996 (Box 90, Folder 8)
      - Vol. 21 (2), Wright, 1996 (Box 90, Folder 9)
      - Vol. 22 (1), Armstrong-Ingram, 1997 (Box 90, Folder 10)
      - Vol. 22 (1), Ericson, 1997 (Box 90, Folder 11)
      - Vol. 22 (1), Hyry/Onuf, 1997 (Box 90, Folder 12)
      - Vol. 22 (1), Jacobs, 1997 (Box 90, Folder 13)
      - Vol. 22 (1), Lasewicz, 1997 (Box 90, Folder 14)
      - Vol. 22 (2), Frevert, 1997 (Box 90, Folder 15)
      - Vol. 22 (2), Hackbart-Dean, 1997 (Box 90, Folder 16)
      - Vol. 22 (2), Jackson, 1997 (Box 90, Folder 17)
      - Vol. 22 (2), O'Toole, 1997 (Box 90, Folder 18)
      - Vol. 22 (2), Paton, 1997 (Box 90, Folder 19)
      - Vol. 23 (1), Bain, 1998 (Box 91, Folder 1)
      - Vol. 23 (1), Bantin, 1998 (Box 91, Folder 2)
      - Vol. 23 (1), Daniels-Howell, 1998 (Box 91, Folder 3)
      - Vol. 23 (1), Greene, 1998 (Box 91, Folder 4)
      - Vol. 23 (1), Marshall, 1998 (Box 91, Folder 5)
      - Vol. 23 (2), Gilliland-Swetland, 1998 (Box 91, Folder 6)
      - Vol. 23 (2), Shelstad, 1998 (Box 91, Folder 7)
      - Vol. 23 (2), Tatem, 1998 (Box 91, Folder 8)
      - Vol. 23 (2), Walters, 1996-1998 (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - 9. Newsletter Editorial Board, 1972-2001
    Newsletter Editorial Board files mainly consist of correspondence pertaining to newsletter articles, announcements, and columns, including the "Institutional Spotlight" column, which focused on a specific repository. Also included are newsletter reports and procedures.
    - Correspondence, 1972-1978 (Box 101, Folder 1-2)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1992 (Box 101, Folder 3-4)
    - "Institutional Spotlight," Correspondence, 1982-1986 (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - Reports and Procedures, 1998-2001 (Box 101, Folder 6)
  - 10. Public Information Officer, 1986-1990
    Files contain publicity information, and include files pertaining to the MAC brochure, MAC logo, and awards.
    - Brochures, 1988-1989 (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Budget Reports, 1988-1989 (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1987-1990 (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with MAC President, 1987-1989 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - Database, 1987-1989 (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - Emeritus Award, 1988-1989 (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Guidelines, 1989 (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Logo Design, 1988 (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - Newsletter Articles, 1987-1989 (Box 102, Folder 9)
    - Officers and Council Press Releases, 1988-1990 (Box 102, Folder 10)
    - Position Description and Background Materials, 1986-1987 (Box 102, Folder 11)
    - President's Award, 1986-1989 (Box 102, Folder 12-13)
    - Public Relations Workshop, 1987-1989 (Box 102, Folder 14-15)
    - Raiders of the Lost Archives, undated (Box 102, Folder 16)
    - Reports, 1987-1990 (Box 102, Folder 17)
    - Revenge of the Raiders of the Lost Archives, 1986 (Box 102, Folder 18)
  - 11. Audio-Visual Materials and Memorabilia, 1972-2004
    - A. Photographs and Slides, 1973-1997
      Series includes photographs and slides, mostly of MAC members at various MAC meetings.
      - Photographs, 1973-1997 (Box 103, Folder 1)
      - Slides, 1986 (Box 103, Folder 2)
    - B. Audio and Videocassettes, 1974-1986
      Series includes cassette and video tapes of Raiders of the Lost Archives productions from 1983 and 1986, and tapes from the Special Projects Committee Seminar on Regional Archival Systems held in July 1974.
      - Raiders of the Lost Archives, 1983, Audio cassette (Box 104, Audio 1)
      - Raiders of the Lost Archives, 1983, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 104, Video 1)
        Use .mp4 access copy
      - Revenge of the Raiders of the Lost Archives, 1986, Videocassette (VHS) (Box 104, Video 2)
      - Special Projects Committee Seminar on Regional Archival Systems, 1974 July 29, Audio cassette (Box 104, Audio 2)
      - Special Projects Committee Seminar on Regional Archival Systems, 1974 July 29, Audio cassette (Box 104, Audio 3)
      - Special Projects Committee Seminar on Regional Archival Systems, 1974 July 29, Audio cassette (Box 104, Audio 4)
      - Special Projects Committee Seminar on Regional Archival Systems, 1974 July 29, Audio cassette (Box 104, Audio 5)
      - Special Projects Committee Seminar on Regional Archival Systems, Evening Session, 1974 July 29, Audio cassette (Box 104, Audio 6)
      - Special Projects Committee Seminar on Regional Archival Systems, Evening Session, 1974 July 29, Audio cassette (Box 104, Audio 7)
      - Special Projects Committee Seminar on Regional Archival Systems, Evening Session, 1974 July 29, Audio cassette (Box 104, Audio 8)
      - Special Projects Committee Seminar on Regional Archival Systems, Morning Session, 1974 July 30, Audio cassette (Box 104, Audio 9)
      - Special Projects Committee Seminar on Regional Archival Systems, Morning Session, 1974 July 30, Audio cassette (Box 104, Audio 10)
      - Special Projects Committee Seminar on Regional Archival Systems, Morning Session, 1974 July 30, Audio cassette (Box 104, Audio 11)
    - C. Memorabilia, 1972-2004
      Series contains memorabilia such as buttons, T-shirts, proclamations and resolutions, and various items that were distributed at MAC meetings.
      - Baseball cap, undated (Box 105)
      - Buttons
        - Committee, undated (Box 106)
        - Midwest Archives Conference, undated (Box 106)
        - Quad Cities, Iowa/Illinois, undated (Box 106)
        - Round 'em up, Move 'em out!, Kansas, 1995 (Box 106)
        - Saint Paul, undated (Box 106)
        - Welcome, undated (Box 106)
      - Mug, 1972-1992, 1992 (Box 106)
      - Name Tags, J. Frank Cook, 1992, 1994, undated (Box 106)
      - Proclamations
        - Office of the Mayor, Chicago, 1997 (Box 107)
        - State of Illinois, 1982 (Box 107)
      - Resolution, City of Cleveland, 1992 (Box 107)
      - Resolution of Welcome, City of Cleveland, 2000 (Box 107)
      - Sign, 1972-1997, 1997 (Box 107)
      - T-Shirts
        - Mad-City MAC, 1996 (Box 105)
        - Midwest Archives Conference, undated (Box 105)
        - Midwest Archives Conference, Milwaukee, 2004 (Box 105)
        - Motley's MACaroons, undated (Box 105)
        - Raiders of the Lost Archives, SAA, 1983 (Box 105)
        - Take a Walk on the Wild Side, Hudson, 1986 (Box 105)
- Archival Issues Editorial Board Records, 2011-2014, Accession 2013-051; .8 cubic ft. (2 boxes); Additions of records from Barbara Floyd, Archival Issues Editorial Board Chair, dating from 2011 to 2014. Files contain the manuscripts, correspondence, assignment of rights forms, and other items related to articles and book reviews accepted for publication in Archival Issues.